export const GOVERNMENTA2020 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. In modern democracy, a government is _________",
A: "a contrast between the rulers and the ruled",
B: "a preserve of the political party in power",
C: "monopoly of the ethnic group",
D: "alternation of power between the majority and minority tribes",
answer: "A. a contrast between the rulers and the ruled",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. The ability to make and enforce laws and administer justice constitute the major functions of a _________",
A: "nation",
B: "society",
C: "government",
D: "pressure group",
answer: "D. Council of Ministers",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. Execute power in a cabinet system of government is vested in the ________",
A: "legislature",
B: "judiciary",
C: "civil service",
D: "council of ministers",
answer: "A. legislature",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. A feature of a confederal state is that _______",
A: "it is a single sovereign state",
B: "its constitution is flexible",
C: "any unit can secede at will",
D: "its powers are distributed equally between the centre and units",
answer: "C. any unit can secede at will",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. One of the limitations to the principles of rule of law is _________",
A: "Immunity",
B: "equality",
C: "liberty",
D: "impartiality",
answer: "A. Immunity",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. Countries adopt unitary system of government because it __________",
A: "detests dictatorship",
B: "promote national integration",
C: "concentrates power only at the centre",
D: "allows the component units to secede at will",
answer: "B. promote national integration",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. Which of the following is an advantage of monocephalous executive ___________",
A: "sharing of power",
B: "quick decision making",
C: "impartial dispension of justice",
D: "enjoyment of press freedom",
answer: "B. quick decision making",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. A major difference between power and authority is that, authority is ________",
A: "scarcely exercised",
B: "more dependent on coercion",
C: "acquired popularly",
D: "exercised through force",
answer: "C. acquired popularly",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. Political participation can take the form of __________",
A: "belonging to a trade union",
B: "being a member of a pressure group",
C: "canvassing for votes",
D: "organizing festival for good harvest",
answer: "C. canvassing for votes",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. Which of the following is a disadvantage of proportional representation?",
A: "encourages rigging",
B: "promotes strong government",
C: "makes for easy decision making in parliament",
D: "is difficult and cumbersome to operate",
answer: "D. Is difficult and cumbersome to operate",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. The sum total of authority in a state unrestrained by law is _______",
A: "monarchy",
B: "society",
C: "oligarchy",
D: "sovereign",
answer: "D. Sovereignty",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. The flexibility and rigidity of constitution refer to the __________",
A: "sources of constitution",
B: "making of constitution",
C: "ease of amending constitution",
D: "coding of constitution",
answer: "C. ease of amending constitution",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. The observance of Rule of Law in a state requires _________",
A: "an independent judiciary",
B: "an ineffective police system",
C: "a flexible constitution",
D: "existence of a two-party system",
answer: "A. an independent judiciary",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. The principle of separating the judiciary from the other organs of government and making it free from executive and legislative influence is termed __________",
A: "judiciary",
B: "judicial review",
C: "separation of powers",
D: "fusions of powers",
answer: "A. Judicial Independence",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. The right to respect the personality of the individual is a _________",
A: "civil right",
B: "natural right",
C: "social right D. economic right",
D: "*******************************",
answer: "B. Natural right",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. Which of the following constitutional provisions gives a high degree of autonomy to component parts of a unitary state?",
A: "Devolution",
B: "Delegation",
C: "Divestiture",
D: "Declaration",
answer: "A. Devolution",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. The following are redresses available at the courts for aggrieved people except _________",
A: "injunction",
B: "mandamus",
C: "certiorari",
D: "prorogation",
answer: "D. prorogation",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. Which of the following usually leads to the curtailment of the rights of citizens?",
A: "transitional period",
B: "granting of presidential pardon",
C: "period pf constitutional pardon",
D: "violent socio-political unrest",
answer: "D. violent socio-political unrest",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. The national secretariat of a political party is managed by the ________",
A: "presidential candidate",
B: "funding members",
C: "national chairman and general secretary",
D: "national executive and youth organizer",
answer: "C. national chairman and general secretary",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. The type of election which allows party members to elect candidates for elective offices is _________",
A: "general election",
B: "bye election",
C: "direct election",
D: "primary election",
answer: "D. primary election",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. An opposition party which sees itself as ''government -in-waiting'' is called ______",
A: "shadow government",
B: "caretaker government",
C: "national government",
D: "responsible government",
answer: "A. shadow government",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. The document which sets out the programme of a political party and guides the electorate to vote for it is the ________",
A: "constitution",
B: "electoral register",
C: "manifesto",
D: "white paper",
answer: "C. manifesto",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. An advantage of a two-party system is that it __________",
A: "simplifies the electoral process",
B: "ensures winner takes all",
C: "protects the electoral commission",
D: "protects the electorate from votr buying",
answer: "A. simplifies the electoral process",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. Which of the following is a non-partisan organization with the aim of influencing government policies?",
A: "Political party",
B: "Pressure group",
C: "Humanitarian",
D: "Relief organization",
answer: "B. Pressure group",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. The collective views held by majority of citizens of a country about a particular policy is _________",
A: "national interest",
B: "public opinion",
C: "commentary",
D: "bullentin",
answer: "B. public opinion",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. An institution under the executive arm of government responsible for formulating and implementing government policies is the ________",
A: "public service",
B: "public corporation",
C: "civil service",
D: "judicial service",
answer: "C. civil service",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. The following are means of controlling public corporation except _________",
A: "legislative control",
B: "judicial control",
C: "ministerial control",
D: "chief of staff control",
answer: "D. chief of staff control",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. The institution established by the constitution to be responsible for recruiting personnel into the civil service is the ___________",
A: "personnel management office",
B: "office of the president",
C: "National labour commission",
D: "Public service commission",
answer: "D. Public service commission",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. If a winner emerges in an election as a result of his/her votes being more than the combined votes of the opposing contestants; what types of electoral system is being practised?",
A: "Absolute majority",
B: "plurality",
C: "second ballot",
D: "alternative vote",
answer: "A. Absolute majority",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. Which of the following is a function of an electoral commission?",
A: "adjudicating election petitions",
B: "provision of electoral registers",
C: "disciplining personnel in the civil service",
D: "promotion of public servants",
answer: "B. provision of electoral registers",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. Which of the following is not an electoral malpratice?",
A: "impersonation",
B: "threatening",
C: "campaigning for a candidate",
D: "gerrymandering",
answer: "C. campaigning for a candidate",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. Local government sources of revenue can best be improved through?",
A: "schools",
B: "the collection of import duties",
C: "the provision of housing units",
D: "cottage industries",
answer: "D. cottage industries",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. Public opinion is important in that, it ________",
A: "helps political parties to assess their policies",
B: "creates delays in the execution of policies",
C: "may be unreliable and misleading",
D: "can be manipulated by political opponents",
answer: "A. helps political parties to assess their policies",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. One of the features of pressure groups is that all members ________",
A: "are rich",
B: "think in the same way",
C: "have similar interests",
D: "oppose the government",
answer: "C. have similar interests",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. Which of the following modes of operation of pressure group undermines economics, social and political stability of the state ________",
A: "Lobbying",
B: "symposia",
C: "strikes",
D: "debates",
answer: "C. strikes",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. The police reform all the following functions except ________",
A: "Public execution of law breakers",
B: "prosecuting law breakers",
C: "protection of life and property",
D: "enforcement of law and order",
answer: "A. Public execution of law breakers",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. Which of the following is a reason for the failure of the assimilation policy in French West Africa?",
A: "The change in name of their culture",
B: "The refusal of the African to be culturally colonized",
C: "The paternal policy of the French",
D: "Bribery of the opinion leaders by the French",
answer: "B. The refusal of the African to be culturally colonized",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. The capital of the French Federation of West Africa states was located in?",
A: "Bamako, Mali",
B: "Dakar, Senegal",
C: "Conakry. Guinea",
D: "Niamey,Niger",
answer: "B. Dakar, Senegal",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. Under the crown colony system of administration, major policies were implemented in the colonies by the ________",
A: "Chiefs and their elders",
B: "Secretary of states for the colonies",
C: "Chiefs and the British",
D: "Colonial governor",
answer: "D. Colonial governor",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. One way of improving productivity in the public service is through?",
A: "promotion without examination",
B: "higher salaries and allowances",
C: "increase in working hours",
D: "open door policy",
answer: "B. higher salaries and allowances",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question41",
question:  "41. Which of the following made the colonial Government a ' Virtual Dictator'?",
A: "Legislative council",
B: "Executive council",
C: "appointment of departmental heads",
D: "Reserved veto powers",
answer: "D. Reserved veto powers",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question42",
question:  "42. Which of the following is a feature of the French policy of Association?",
A: "Elevation of the position of the chiefs",
B: "French citizenship to subjects",
C: "scholarships to needy students",
D: "language barrier and race",
answer: "A. Elevation of the position of the chiefs",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question43",
question:  "43. The African Union is most often unable to resolve conflicts because of _________",
A: "financial weekness",
B: "absence of African High Command",
C: "Differences in Culture",
D: "Language barrier and race",
answer: "B. Absence of African High Command",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question44",
question:  "44. The formation of the African Union is aimed at achieving a wider goal of ________",
A: "cultural integration",
B: "continental government",
C: "national solidarity",
D: "African identity",
answer: "A. Cultural integration",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question45",
question:  "45. A major advantage of a country's foreign policy is that, it __________",
A: "encourages infringement on the territories of other states",
B: "promotes the country's national interest",
C: "stimulates political activities in the state",
D: "promotes understanding between the leaders and the led",
answer: "B. Promotes the country’s national interest",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question46",
question:  "46. The West African Students Union (WASU) was formed by _______",
A: "Siaka Stevens",
B: "K. A. Gbedemah",
C: "E.F Small",
D: "OLadipo Solake",
answer: "D. OLadipo Solake",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question47",
question:  "47. A military coup d'etat is followed by _________",
A: "enforcement of fundamental human rights",
B: "suspension of the constitution",
C: "breaking of diplomatic relations with foreign countries",
D: "mass importation of firearms",
answer: "B. suspension of the constitution",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question48",
question:  "48. Which of the following countries is a Unitary?",
A: "Nigeria",
B: "Egypt",
C: "Ghana",
D: "Canada",
answer: "C. Ghana",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question49",
question:  "49. Which of the following does not influence a country's foreign policy?",
A: "Desire for foreign investments",
B: "International law, Conventions and Treaties",
C: "Religion and racial factors",
D: "Age of the leader",
answer: "D. Age of the leader",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question50",
question:  "50. The National Congress of British West Africa (NCBWA) was founded in _______",
A: "Sierra Leone",
B: "Liberia",
C: "Ghana",
D: "Nigeria",
answer: "C. Ghana",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},


]